Hello programmer, welcome back to our SQL TQL series.
So today we're going to explore the three-power fully aggregate function in the SQL,
like the count sum and the average.
And this function alerts us to perform the calculation on the report.
So first of all, simply just define for the SQL aggregate function.
So here, the sum count and average function in the SQL.
Are used to perform the calculation on groups of record.
And they are incredibly useful for summarizing the data.
So now let's explore for how they all put some example, okay?
So first of all, create the example of counting the number of records, okay?
So just go here and first of all, here I can just type select and also type the count.
And they are just used for this star sign and now use the edge statement and then type for here the total employees, okay?
From the employees table, okay?
So PLO employees, so this one is perfect and here the complete employees.
And this statement here I can use the count function to count all records in the employees table.
And first of all, I can select.
So here now first I can select and then execute now here.
You can see here perfectly create for the total employees number of file.
Okay, so here completely query will return the total number of employees as the total employees.
Okay, and there is the total employees column and next step here I can create for calculating the sum, okay?
So now just go here and first of all here, give the count, okay, and here I can insert for the sum value.
So sum for here the salary range, okay?
So the salary column and use for here the total salary, okay?
So just simply just type the total salary and there I have perfectly using the sum function to calculate the total salary of all employees, okay?
So first of all, I can select and execute and see the result and now just to it.
Okay, so we have this and you can see here the total salary and amount, okay?
So this query returns the sum of all salaries as the total salary column.
Okay, so I hope you perfectly understand this.
Next, I can create the calculating the average function, okay?
So now just try, so first of all, simply change for the sum and there I can just simply create for the average, okay?
And in this insert, I can change for the salary column and insert for here the age column, okay?
Now here I can just type for the average age, okay, average age from the employee stable.
And this table using the average function to calculate the average age of all employees in the employee stable, okay?
So now just take the first of all, I can select all the query and then execute and see the result you can see here the average age of the employee table is 29, okay?
So here I completely return the average age of the employee and employees, okay?
And next step here, I can just simply define the example, so here apply the condition to the aggregate function, okay?
So first of all, just go here and now just change this, okay?
And now here I can create for the user again, the account function and here I can create for the as a total female employee.
Okay, so now just type the total female employee and next step here, I can create use the OIR clause for the gender, okay?
So define perfectly the gender is equal to, so now here define this is the female, okay?
So perfectly just type this is the female and now just use here again the account function to count the number of female employees in the employee stable, okay?
So now just try and see the result for the create, so first of all select and then execute now you can see here I cannot define for the gender column, okay?
So simply just open for here the employee table, so now just use again the define for the, for and now define for the gender column, okay?
So here simply just type the select start from here, the employee stable and first of all select the execute now, you can see here this is only used to the total six column employee ID, first name last name salary and the department and here you can see first the female column and the row and there the salary, this the female and there step for the table, the five row and the two row.
And the female employee, okay, so I hope you perfectly understand it and there you have it the perfect overview of the count some and diverse function in the SQL with some practical example, I hope you found this tutorial helpful so stay tuned for more SQL tips and tricks, so thank you for watching, okay?